investorscare.com 2014-11-20

# Privacy and Security on FirstGiving

FirstGiving takes your privacy very seriously.

We only pass on your name, email address and mailing address to the nonprofit you are fundraising for, registering for an event with, or donating to, so that they can acknowledge your efforts.

Please note that by visiting or registering with FirstGiving.com, you are agreeing to the practices detailed below so please read on to find out how information relating to you will be treated as you use our site.

  1. ## The information we collect from you as a site visitor

FirstGiving collects information about the Internet Protocol (IP) addresses of all visitors to our site. An IP address is a number assigned to your computer automatically when you use the internet. This information is only collected in aggregate (in other words, we are not able to monitor your individual usage of the site) and helps us monitor site traffic patterns in order to improve our service. 

This site uses cookies for some interactive features. A cookie is a small amount of data, which includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. Most browsers will automatically accept cookies. You can set your browser to reject cookies but some parts of the web site may not function properly if the cookies are rejected.

  2. ## The information we collect from you as a fundraiser or event registrant

When you create a secure personal account on FirstGiving for the purpose of creating a fundraising page or event registration, we collect your title, name, email address, mailing address, your password, and occasionally information required by the nonprofit. We will automatically pass on your name and email and home addresses to the nonprofit that will benefit from the donations you are collecting. In all other instances, we will not pass on this information to any third party unless you give us your express consent.
  3. ## The information we collect from you when you donate

If you donate on FirstGiving, we collect your first and last name, credit or debit card details (including card type, card number and expiry date) and billing address. We will only use your payment details for the purpose of processing your donation via our payment partner [Litle & Co](http://www.litle.com/). To find out more about the security of your payments, please read our Security Policy. We will automatically pass on your name and email and home addresses to the nonprofit that will benefit from your donation.
  4. ## Email newsletters from FirstGiving

We will send you email newsletters; however you can opt-out at any time as all newsletters from FirstGiving include the option to unsubscribe.
  5. ## Nonprofits use of your personal information

FirstGiving passes along personal information to the nonprofit you have fundraised for, registered for an event with, or donated to. If you wish to stop receiving further communications from a nonprofit, please contact them directly.
  6. ## Security precautions to protect your information

The transfer of online transaction data to and from the web site is protected by the implementation of a Secure Sockets Layer protocol. Our Verisign 128-bit secure certificate allows web browsers to verify the authenticity of our secure.FirstGiving.com domain and to communicate with our site securely, protecting confidential information from interception and hacking. It is your responsibility to keep your password secure at all times to avoid unauthorized use of your FirstGiving account.
  7. ## Share-this-pageservices

When you provide a friends email address for FirstGiving to forward a web address, we guarantee that we will only use your friends address for this purpose.
  8. ## Legal Process

Although unlikely, FirstGiving may be forced by law to provide personally identifiable information to the appropriate authorities.
  9. ## Acceptance of our Privacy Policy

Use of the FirstGiving website and associated services implies acceptance of this Privacy Policy. If you are not satisfied with any aspect of it please do not continue to use the website and services. This policy may change from time to time and you are deemed to have accepted the current version each time you use FirstGiving.com or any site powered by us.

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy please contact us via email at [support@firstgiving.com](mailto:support@firstgiving.com)
